good afternoon uh I'm Jan uh I had the
bfsi business for Mo engage uh thanks a
lot for joining
today uh so yes the Hot Topic today for
uh you know is embeded
Insurance I've just cre three or four
questions for you I'll not burn much of
your time so my first query to you uh
would be how do you think the concept of
uh embedded Insurance evolved in recent
years and what key factors have driven
its RIS arise to prominence in today's
modern
era so jatin uh I think we were
conversing outside also not too long ago
in the distant past getting insurance
was like watching how paint dries up it
was very exciting but now insurance is
just like that cool kid around the
corner who is making its way into our
lives embedded into just everything you
book a ticket on Red Bus and pay just 12
extra and get your trip insured so it's
just about everything that requires
embed that is coming with embedded
insurance and this is helping not only
the consumers because they know that
they can go on a holiday with peace of
mind they can carry valuable stuff on a
small trip in a cab trip from Navi
Mumbai to South Mumbai trips are now
embedded with insurance so it's like
it's become like the cool kid and with
the tech
Revolution and it's growing Leaps and
Bounds so that's what I mean and what do
you why do you think uh that it has
grown so fast first is obviously the
consumer
demand the a consumer today demands uh
his um uh the things to be insured like
I said a Ola trip from Navi Mumbai to
South Mumbai why do you think people buy
insurance for that trip what have you
ever taken that insurance when you uh
book a Ola or a uber how many of you
have taken that insurance by the way
while traveling through
cab very good
jalpa why would you uh do an insurance I
know you are from insurance and she's
from ICC Lombard jalpa momaya would you
like to share
uh it is just a kind of security what
you get in terms of you buy a mobile
phone you book a travel or anything it
is just that
okay it is one giving us an assurance
that what you're expecting is going to
happen and if not there's a cover to
you're insured you're taken care of yeah
I think so that's peace of mind you
heard the consumer talking so why
embedded insurance is becoming one is
the consumer demand secondly I said
technology has paved the way so you
remember the Earth while Bollywood
Thrillers where a typical story starts
from a small child uh having a good
friendship and from an old family
becomes a rich millionaire etc etc gets
into Bad Company so like like in the
same manner Insurance also initially was
conventionally sold by agents but now
like we said and I'm rehydrating again
you can get insurance on any app like
phone she spoke about a phone go to buy
a phone at a Reliance Digital or a vij
sales they'll ask you do you want a
cover how many do you want an extended
cover this is the warranty that you get
along with it so those kind of things
additionally data analytics the
explosion on data and the availability
of data and the tools to analyze the
data have paved the way for bringing
embedded Insurance in the Forefront for
all products and services that you buy
so that is the third thing that is uh
created the um leap the growth in
embedded insurance and the most
important factor is it is just good
business right embedded in insurance is
very good business it creates additional
revenue streams for the organizations
and more value for
customers so if I'm buying an iPhone
which is costing me one and a half lakhs
and if the phone decides to delve into a
pool I know that I'm taken care of and
embedded insurance is there for my
rescue so that's uh I own an iPhone yeah
and definitely I've gone for one so
that's peace of mind yes yeah so very
well put ma'am uh so yeah uh I
understand the data analytics the
technology behind it it all plays a
pivotal role over here and I believe
that is where you know the technology
companies like Mo engage comes into play
wherein you know the the correct
recommendation is put further in front
of each of the customers so does this
customer prefer prefer a travel
insurance or a specific insurance
related to the product that is well
placed over there right so that
understanding of that behavioral aspect
of the customer plays a pivotal role so
I'll move into the next question
uh so embeded insurance is often hailed
for its ability to provide uh
personalized coverage but we discuss how
the customization is achieved and the
role technology plays uh in tailoring
Insurance solution to individual needs
also uh what are the typical challenges
and the opportunities does this level of
personalization
present so um I'll just open up a
question to the audience how many of you
have got a suit or a costume design
through a designer to your custom fit
anybody for a special occasion I've gone
through an experience anything that
you've done that then he's my customer
today he'll answer the questions for you
so what what is it that you would choose
for your so since it's your suit what
are the things that come to your mind
when you want to get it tailored or
custom fit to your
requirements probably the fabric and the
fitting I would say fabric color the
occasion depending on the occasion Etc
so embedded insurance is just like that
it custom fits to your needs and you can
choose now what are the like unlike in a
suit when you're choosing the fabric
thread the designer Etc in embedded
Insurance what you will look for is what
is it that it covers what are the risk
coverages how uh what are the other
benefits in terms of the servicing that
it helps you what is the claim process
so that is what embedded Insurance uh
the uh Dynamic aspects or personalizing
embedded Insurance you would look into
these parameters when you choose an
embedded insurance and once you do that
like when you uh created your suit and
when you chose everything of your uh
choice and when you wore it the feeling
is like unexplainable right you don't
want to come out of it so it's that is
the peace of mind and insurer gets when
you you meet the c or you customize it
and personalize it for him then the
customer stickiness with embedded
insurance with all these things that you
personalize for him that for example if
you have a solo policy the customer does
not need a maternity cover and if he's
of young age he doesn't need some very B
and is living a healthy lifestyle he
would need a basic health insurance or a
comprehensive cover which takes care of
his he might have be happy with value
added services on well his benefits if
he's going to the gym Etc so if you
personalize that that for him depending
on what his personality type is what
more could he ask for right and for
example he's uh a Avid Gym U uh Fitness
free and if you have a topup plan for
gym or some discount coupons on the key
leading uh gyms around his City I think
he or she wouldn't ask for more so
that's the kind of customization and
personalization but that's possible with
the explosion of data and you knowing
the customer and at the same time
information security is of prime
importance because your uh customer
would not like you to know what pizza
topping he likes or what Netflix Channel
he's binging on so you have to be very
careful by using when you use these data
analytics yeah thank you uh I'll move
towards the second uh third question
basically uh so embed Insurance the risk
exist for both customers and businesses
so uh as embeded Insurance safeguards
Financial Futures uh what role does it
play in mitigating risk for both
customers and businesses and also how
can the integrated approach contribute
to Greater Financial resilience uh in
the face of un foreen
events okay so I think the pretty much
the answers don't change like for
example uh consumers who take embedded
insurance and we just spoke it's like
that tailored suit which you have
created to your fit right it's like a
cozy safe blanket whether it is travel
you get coverage on everything whether
it is travel mishaps product failures it
is basically there to take care of you
now businesses are providing this with
confidence because they are able to do
the necessary Innovations with the techn
uh technological Advance advancements we
able to take calculated risk and the
customers know they have a safety net to
fall back on
right so these uh these are couple of
things that we feel
um in terms of mitigating risk that you
spoke about so uh thank you for that
I'll move into the last and final
question for this uh session so with the
advancements in technology including iot
and AI how is data being leveraged and
embedded Insurance to enhance risk
assessment streamland clean processes
and ultimately improve the overall
efficiency of the insurance ecosystem
that is first uh what ethical
considerations should be taken into
account in the era of data driven
insurance so I'll answer the first
question the first part of the question
one is uh you said in the iot and the
artificial intelligence is how we are
leveraging the embedded insurance so at
ICC Lombard we have couple of uh the
most important use case which is claim
servicing which is in General Insurance
The Moment of Truth for the customer on
claim service say we've used technology
to its Optimum best whether it is
intimating claim on a visual call assist
feature which we use where the customer
basically gets an SMS and on clicking
the link in the SMS there is an assisted
ivr system which guides the customer to
fill up the claim details in the event
of a motor claim uh uh in the event of
an accident and the customer wants to
intimate a motor claim this service is
available 24x7
customer can intimate the claim on the
go wherever in the event of an accident
he does not need to wait for long cues
at the call center or have a whole time
and he gets the claim number instantly
even claim document upload insta spect
everything is uh based on artificial
intelligence and the customer can do the
survey himself upload the images in the
event of an accident and the survey is
completed you don't need to physic you
to just submit the vehicle to the garage
so on claim servicing that's again a
pathbreaking
um pathbreaking digital Journey that we
have the claim status is available to
the customer on the go on our WhatsApp
handle and on our voice bots so we have
voicebot where we using iot machine
learning and uh the artificial
intelligence we have trained robots we
use basically a customer communication
mascot which is a virtual uh responsive
agent we call Ria so is our customer
communication mascot so claim services
uh almost 90% on our motor claim
inations we are we are doing digital
inations and customer does not have to
wait so that's a big number and that's
how it has helped us go a long way and
even on claim statuses almost about
40,000 transactions on claim statuses
are done digitally in the maret so those
are the kind of things and when you talk
about ethical framework what we'd like
to say is we want to be not only right
we want to be fair and just in all our
practices with the customer so every
claim every fi every um every use case
or every Journey that a customer has
where there is a financial impact on the
customer our policies processes our
focus is on being fair and just to the
customer while you know that insurance
policies come with a lot of riders few
Riders are for compliance or regulatory
uh Riders few are obviously embedded in
the product that the customer has bought
so one is we try and be as much as
transparent as we can in all our
Communications that we do with the
customer so that customer does not have
surprises at the time of claims Etc and
um uh one is transparency in
communication two is ensuring that we
are updating our customer at every step
of his journey so we don't keep things
to ourself at every step even if there
is a delay if there's a claim that's
going into an investigation rest assured
that the customer is informed of what's
happening and it's not only the customer
our partners are equally updated so we
also have a agent WhatsApp Handler where
our agents can get the status of the
claims of the customers maap to them so
we take care on both the sides it's not
that just the customer is being updated
in the event it's a partner a claim from
a agents customer even the agent is kept
a so being fair and just is our uh AR
key mantras for being in the ethical
practices great ma'am uh lot of great
insights so yeah EMB insurance is the
next big product in the insurance space
and yes all the Tech Industries are will
be coming up with much more better
products I I believe in the market to
address this and you know uh generate
better Revenue out of these things and I
hope companies like IC Lombard and Tech
Partners like Moes actually dwell deep
into it and uh make it a success thanks
a lot for your time so much any
questions we'll be happy to
take